Guide to the Henry Muhlenberg Hiester Papers, 1807-1928 (bulk 1872-1919) and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Henry Muhlenberg Hiester papers 1807-1928 (bulk 1872-1919) and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Hiester, Henry Muhlenberg, ca. 1850-1916.
4.0 linear feet Extent: 3,978 Items
Lawyer of Mercersburg, Pennsylvania. Correspondence, personal, and business papers of Henry Muhlenberg Hiester and sister Maria C. M. Hiester. Contains much genealogical information. Also includes the correspondence of Dr. Joseph M. Hiester and letters from H. W. Freedley concerning his service in the Union Army during the Civil War. There are a number of account books for various milling operations run by the Hiester family, including Millmont Mills, Montgomery Mills, Hiester and Hain, and Hiester and Shippen.
RL.00539
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Henry Muhlenberg Hiester Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1948.
Collection Overview
Correspondence, personal, and business papers of Henry Muhlenberg Hiester and sister Maria C. M. Hiester. Contains much genealogical information. Also includes the correspondence of Dr. Joseph M. Hiester and letters from H. W. Freedley concerning his service in the Union Army during the Civil War. There are a number of account books for various milling operations run by the Hiester family, including Millmont Mills, Montgomery Mills, Hiester and Hain, and Hiester and Shippen.
Subject Headings
Freedley, H. W.; Hiester, Henry Muhlenberg, ca. 1850-1916; Hiester and Hain (Mercersburg, Pa.); Hiester and Shippen (Mercersburg, Pa.); Millmont Mills (Mercersburg, Pa.); Montgomery Mills (Mercersburg, Pa.); United States. Army -- Military life; Flour mills -- Pennsylvania; Soldiers -- United States -- Correspondence; Industries -- Pennsylvania; Mercersburg (Pa.) -- Commerce; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865
Contents of Collection
- Henry Muhlenberg Hiester Papers, 1807-1928 (bulk 1872-1919) and undated, (10 boxes)
  Printed material in Box 10 consists of calling cards and invitations. Boxes 6 and 10 are unprocessed.
  - Papers, 1807-1890 (Box 1)
  - Papers, 1891-1901 (Box 2)
  - Papers, 1902-1907 (Box 3)
  - Papers, 1908-1916 (Box 4)
  - Papers, 1917-1928 and undated (Box 5)
  - Invitations, 1859-1911 and undated (Box 6)
  - Papers, undated (Box 7)
  - Papers, undated, (3 folders) (Box 8)
  - Printed Material, 1894-1921 and undated, (1 folder) (Box 8)
  - Papers, undated (Box 9)
  - Papers, undated, (1 folder) (Box 10)
  - Printed Material, 1894-1921 and undated, (2 folders)
  - Bound Volumes
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume M:3240)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume M:5332)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume M:5333)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume M:5334)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume M:5335)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume S:5336)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume L:5337)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume M:5846)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume S:5847)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume L:5848)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume L:5849)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume L:5850)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume L:5851)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume M:5852)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume L:5853)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume F:5854)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume M:5855)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume M:5855)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume L:5856)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume F:5857)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume L:5858)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume F:5859)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume F:5860)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume F:5861)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume F:5862)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume F:5863)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume F:5864)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume L:5865)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume L:5866)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume L:5867)
    - Bound manuscript volume (Volume F:5870)